Bertha Schooler Sohn map collection
Geography and Map Division, Library of Congress
Bertha Schooler Sohn map collection 1932-1994
G3700 coll .S6 Sohn
Sohn, Bertha Schooler
75 items
3 folders
Geography and Map Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
The collection consists of seventy-five maps depicting locations in the United States, Canada, Mexico, Europe, and Japan.
Provenance
Bertha Schooler Sohn donated the materials to the Geography and Map Division in 1996.
Access and Restrictions
The Bertha Schooler Sohn map collection collection is open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Geography and Map Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Biographical Note
Bertha Schooler Soh was born on August 7, 1915 in New York City and died July 31, 2006.
Sohn was a cataloger with the Smithsonian Institution Libraries, Washington, D.C., from 1963 to 1987.
Thereafter, she worked as a freelance researcher and translator and volunteered in the library of the Adas Israel Congregation, Washington, D.C.
She was a member of the Jewish Genealogical Society of Greater Washington.
Scope and Content Note
The collection consists of seventy-five maps depicting locations in the United States, Canada, Mexico, Europe, and Japan.
Arrangement
The Bertha Schooler Sohn map collection collection is organized in a single series with subseries for each geographic area.
Series I: Bertha Schooler Sohn map collection
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Sohn, Bertha Schooler, 1915-2006, compiler.
Places
Canada--Maps.; Europe--Maps.; Japan--Maps.; Mexico--Maps.; United States--Maps.
Form/Genre
Maps.
Container List
- Bertha Schooler Sohn map collection (Folder 1 - 3)
  75 items
  - Alaska
    1 item
    - The Matanuska Valley: Southcentral Alaska road and recreation map, 1976
  - Arizona
    2 items
    - Arizona road map, 198-
      Arizona Highways Magazine.
    - Grand Canyon National Park, 1987
  - Connecticut
    - Connecticut official 1981-1982 transportation and recreation map, 1982-1983
      National Park Service.
  - Arkansas, Louisiana, Mississippi
    - Exxon map, 1976
  - Delaware, District of Columbia, Maryland, Virginia, and West Virginia
    - Exxon map, 1973
    - AAA map, 1986
  - Eastern United States
    4 items
    - Citgo map, 1972
    - Exxon map, 1976
    - Exxon map, 1978
    - AAA map, 1981
  - Florida
    8 items
    - Florida tourguide vacation map, 1972
      Gulf Oil.
    - Miami Beach, Fort Lauderdale area, 1974
    - Florida official road map, 1975
      Department of Transportation.
    - Exxon map of Florida, 1975
    - Greater Sarasota street map
      First Federal Savings.
    - Dolph's indexed street map - Jupiter through Lake Worth
    - Greater Orlando
      Flagship Bank of Florida.
    - Singer Island. Directory and map. Riveria Beach and Palm Beach shores.
      Singer Island Businessmen's Assocation.
  - Illinois
    - Illinois official highway map, 1953
      State of Illinois.
    - Illinois official highway map, 1980
  - Indianapolis
    - AAA map
    - Iowa
    - Guide to streets and public transportation in Greater Iowa City, 1980
    - Iowa official state transportation map, 1981
      Iowa City Chamber of Commerce.
  - Kansas and Nebraska
    - Phillips 66, 1974
  - Kentucky and Tennessee
    - Phillips 66, 1968
      Includes Greater Louisville.
  - Maryland
    - Batimore and vicinity, 1969
      Esso.
    - Batimore and vicinity, 1973
      Exxon.
  - Massachussetts
    - Boston and vicinity, 1968
      Includes Cape Cod.
  - Nevada
    - Nevada, 1973
      Chevron.
      Standard Oil of California.
    - Las Vegas City map, 1973
      Greater Las Vegas Chamber of Commerce.
  - New Jersey
    - Mobil map, 1970
    - Texaco map, 1970
  - New York
    11 items
    - Esso map, 1971
    - Citgo map, 1972
    - Exxon map, 1976
    - Buffalo and vicinity, 1936
      Standard Oil of New York.
    - Guide to Letchworth Park, State of New York, 1935
      Genesee State Park Commission.
    - Map showing highways, public campsites and historic sites in the Adirondack and Catskill Mountains of the New York State Forest Preserve, 1932
      Conservation Department, State of New York.
    - Long Island and New York City, 1964
      Mobil.
    - Long Island / Westchester County, 1969
      American Oil Co.
    - New York City and Long Island, 1967
      Esso
    - New York City and Long Island, 1977
  - North Carolina and South Carolina
    - Esso map, 1970
  - Ohio
    - Humble map, 1969
  - Pennsylvania
    - Amoco Oil Co. map, 1974
    - Exxon map, 1976
    - Exxon map, 1980
    - Texaco map, 1972
  - Tennesee and Kentucky
    - Esso map, 1968
  - Texas
    - American Oil Co., 1964
  - Virginia
    - Maps of Frederick County and Winchester, Virginia, 1986
  - Washington, D.C.
    - Map and vistor's guide, 1975
      Exxon
    - Map and vistor's guide, 1976
  - Western and Central United States
    - Phillips 66, 1966
  - Canada
    7 items
    - Atlantic provinces, featuring city area map of Halifax, 1969
    - Manitoba / Saskatchewan, featuring city area maps of Thunder Bay and Winnipeg, 1971
      Shell Oil.
    - Montreal, 1970
    - Ontario featuring city area maps of Hamilton, downtown Ottawa, and metropolitan Toronto, 1971
      Shell.
    - Ontario, 1972
    - Metropolitan Toronto, 1994
    - Quebec, 1972
  - Mexico
    - Mapa turistico, 1984
  - England
    - Geographer's map of London
    - Newcastle upon Tyme
  - France
    - Chaumont-Strassbourg
      Michelin 62.
    - Verdun-Wissembourg
      Michelin 57.
  - Greece
    - Large road map
  - Netherlands
    - Maastricht
  - Scotland
    - Glasgow and the west
      Guide map and a street plan.
  - Sweden
    - Stockholm, 1966
    - Uppsala, 1973
    - Visby, 1972
  - Japan
    - Tourist map of Japan, 1983